One year ago, Google took its biggest L
of all time when it was convicted in
court of being a filthy monopolist and
was forced to join Microsoft on the
registered antitrust offenders list.
Back in the good old days, Google was
making illegal deals to maintain search
engine supremacy, like how it made up
85% of Mozilla's revenue by being the
default search engine. And its insane
deal with Apple, where it paid them 36%
of search revenue to the tune of $20
billion per year. In what appeared to be
a big win for the little guy, a judge
ruled that these deals stifle
competition from other search engines.
And now there's only one thing left to
determine. What would be the appropriate
way to punish Google for these
horrendous violations.
Thank you, sir. May I have another?
Well, yesterday we finally learned
Google's fate, and it's far worse than
we ever could have imagined. It is
September 4th, 2025, and you're watching
the Code Report. Many experts expected
that Google would be forced by the
Department of Justice to sell its
precious Chrome browser, which continues
to dominate with 69% of the total
browser market share. A very fitting
number when you screw over other
companies to reach the top. The Chrome
is basically the lynch pin that ties all
other Google products together, and
losing it would be devastating to their
business. AI companies were praying for
the simulation to make this happen, and
vultures like Perplexity even offered
34.5 billion to buy it. But Perplexity
forgot the most important rule in life.
Nothing ever happens. When people
started predicting Chrome would be spun
off from Google, I made a video
predicting that that would never happen.
And it turns out I was right. Now, I'm
not Quasimoto. It's just the idea that a
massive corporation would actually be
punished for playing unfair is
ludicrous. The punishment that was
actually handed down can best be
described as a slap on the wrist
administered with a feather. Google gets
to keep Chrome. It gets to keep Android.
And it doesn't have to not be evil. On
that news alone, the stock was up 10%
yesterday, which represents hundreds of
billions of dollars in market cap. And
Nancy Pelosi just got richer because she
bought call options on Google a few
months ago that are now deep in the
money. I don't know how she does it, but
the judge didn't totally let Google off
the hook. He administered the wrist slap
by telling Google they have to share
your search data and stop making
exclusive deals with big platforms. In
addition, they're not allowed to bundle
all their apps together for Android
manufacturers. When it comes to sharing
data, I want to make it clear that
they're not sharing all the personal
data that you gave Google willingly.
They're sharing the opaque anonymous
data they've accumulated after years of
crawling the web, which in theory will
help competitors build better search
engines and possibly AI models that
replace search engines. What's kind of
crazy though is that Apple can keep its
11 figure search deal with Google.
I wish I knew how to quit you. They just
have to change the wording in the
contract so that it's not an exclusive
deal. That means that if you want to
start your own search engine, there's
nothing stopping you from becoming the
default search on iPhone. It just offer
Apple more money than Google. In
addition, Mosilla must be happy right
now because they get to keep their
Google money also, which would have
killed their business otherwise. But the
big question is why did Google get off
so easy? Well, Judge Meta said this in
his ruling. The government overreached
in seeking the force sale of these key
assets, which Google did not use to
affect any illegal restraints. He also
said that the emergence of generative AI
has changed the course of this case and
that Google's dominance in search
doesn't carry over to the Gen AI space.
And I would have to agree because there
are superior generative AI tools that
are eating Google's lunch. One of which
is Warp, the sponsor of today's video.
Over 700,000 developers are already
using Warp's development environment,
and they just launched their biggest
upgrade yet, Warp Code. This merges the
Warp Terminal with their IDE into one
platform for writing code with agents.
So, instead of wrangling a bunch of
different AI programming tools, you can
just code on Warp. The built-in code
editor comes with review panels, inline
file editing, and suggested diffs to
help you ship productionready code
faster. It also provides tools like
agent profiles that let you customize
your agents to make them more
contextaware. Warp code just scored
75.8% on swbench which was good enough
to claim the number three spot on the
leaderboard. You can try it out for free
today at warp.dev/moo
firehip or use code moo to get one month
free on the pro plan for just a dollar.
This has been the code report. Thanks
for watching and I will see you in the
next one.